## System engineer

## **Anthony BESCOND**

Mobile: +33 (0)6 87 79 01 99 31 years old

Email: besconda(at)gmail.com

Online: https://redref.github.io/self-resume/



Over ten years in system and applications administration, I acquired a global understanding of differents ways to integrate, push to production and run applications. Those various IT domains and experiences permit me to quickly learn and work in autonomy on new technologies and challenges.

I am looking forward to integrate a new infrastructure and new challenges always with performance, scalability and simplicity in mind.

# Skills and Technologies

**Configuration management:** Puppet, CI/CD **Monitoring:** OpenTSDB, Graphite, ELK, Nagios **Development:** system daemons, micro-services, APIs

Languages: Python, Shell, Javascript, ...

BigData: Hadoop, Elasticsearch, Cassandra, ...

**HPC:** Slurm, Infiniband, Paraview **Storage:** Ceph, MooseFS, NFS

#### Education

Professional degree (Licence) in "Networks administration and security"  $^{200}$ 

Technology degree (DUT) in "Networks and telecommunications"

### Experiences

## System engineer in HPC/BigData

depuis 2014

Ministry of defense (Paris)

Technologies: Puppet, Linux, Python, Django, DRF, Ceph, Infiniband, GPU

Choose hardware according to software benchmarks and problems.

Provision, configure, patch and maintain "bare metal" hardware clusters.

Integrate and optimise HPC and BigData softwares for performance.

Design and develop tools as daemons, APIs or webservices to manage platforms (Pvthon)

Analyse customers applications to optimise workloads.

## **System engineer in e-commerce**

2013 à 2014

Galeries Lafayette (Paris)

**Technologies:** Apache, Varnish, Tomcat, Oracle, Hybris, Graphite

Manage and maintain the 3-tier web platform and product publishing workflows. Design and maintain delivery architecture with test platforms and automatic build processes.

Integrate metrology tools used by the platform capacity planning and marketing.

#### System engineer in HPC

2013

OVH GS - Oxalya (Paris)

Technologies: Linux, Slurm, Lustre, Infiniband, GPU Nvidia

Install, deploy and maintain dedicated HPC clusters in customers offices.

Integrate a "software as a service" offer.

Compile, optimise and benchmark computation softwares.

#### **System administrator**

2010 à 2012

DCNS (Cherbourg)

Technologies: Linux, Oracle, JBOSS, Apache, Tomcat, Java, Centreon; Control-M

Install and maintain industrial applications (stock and workflows) and daily data processes.

Develop tools to ensure a safe and smooth delivery installation process.

#### System administrator "Intelligent Network"

2008 à 2010

Alcatel-Lucent

**Assignments:** Bell M (Canada), OTE (Grèce), Orange (R.Dominicaine).

Technologies: Solaris, Oracle, Switching

Install and deliver IN application cluster and services on customer site.

#### **Network administrator (internship)**

2008

MMF Services (Quéven)

Configure new network stack with internal needs. Integrate web-services as alternatives to VPN.

#### PHP developer (internship)

2007

Solstys (Lannion)

Integrate WebDay protocol in the CMS product by emulation in PHP.

#### **Interests**

Trail running

Development and new technologies (home system, deep learning algorithms, ...)

Online gaming